<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Eric Liu</title>
        <link>https://chy.io/blog/</link>
        <description>Tech and other thoughts.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <item>
            <title>The Internship Search II</title>
            <link>https://chy.io/blog/2017/12/2017-recruiting</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 1 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <description>This is a summary of my experience finding a co-op
                during my junior year at Northeastern and a follow up to my
                internship search last year.

                Here are some stats once again.

                First interview: 8/15 12:30 pm PST
                Last offer signed: 11/2 12:09 pm PST
                Companies applied to: 50+
                Companies interviewed with: 27
                Homework challenges: 10
                Total phone interviews: 34
                Onsites: 9
                Total offers: 14
                Offers accepted: 2
                This year, I was on the search for my third and final co-op at
                Northeastern. I had 6 months free which meant I could do two
                internships; one winter and one summer.

                Having worked at a few medium and large sized tech companies, I
                wanted to try something different this year. My primary goal
                was to gain experience in the financial sector as it has always
                been an interest of mine.

                Beginning in mid-August, I sent out a flurry of applications to
                hedge funds, prop shops, and unicorns. Slowly and surely, the
                Hackerrank challenges began to roll in. Much of the interview
                preparation I did last year managed to carry over. And so, this
                year, I only did two weeks or so of practice to get back into
                shape. My interviews themselves soon turned into practice for
                my other interviews.

                Phone rounds ramped up in September and onsites in October. By
                mid-October, I was dedicating almost all my time to recruiting,
                spending upwards of 40+ hours a week traveling and
                interviewing.

                Having a few internships on my resume meant top companies
                overlooked the fact that I did not attend a "target" school.
                Even though I already had Apple on my resume last year, my
                response rate for online applications this year was almost
                tenfold (~40% vs ~4%). In addition to applying online, I also
                reached out to friends for referrals and recruiters that I had
                talked with in the past.

                3/4 of my classes were on Tuesday/Friday which meant I was
                traveling Monday/Wednesday/Thursday. Over the course of 4
                weeks, I had 2 interviews in NYC, 2 in SF, 2 in Chicago, and 1
                in CT. Unluckily for me, interviews in the same city usually
                were not back to back. This meant many sleepless flights to
                catch up on school work. I was very fortunate that my
                professors were understanding and let me make up any missed
                tests and midterms.

                I had to schedule final round interviews tightly since
                Northeastern doesn't have a recruiting policy for deadlines.
                This meant most offers came with the standard 2 week deadline.
                Though the process was quite stressful, companies were in
                general responsive and flexible.

                By the end of October, I had finished my interviews and was
                hearing back from companies. I was lucky in that, unlike last
                year, most companies got back to me around the same time. I was
                considering Citadel, Robinhood, Quora, and Facebook for winter
                and DRW, Tower Research, Bridgewater, Two Sigma, Affirm, and
                Airbnb for summer.

                Some highlights include: exploring Chicago during my Citadel
                onsite, DRW bringing all the candidates to a nice dinner,
                ordering a lot of take-out sushi, almost missing a flight to
                SF, having a hotel scheduled for the wrong night in SF, and
                Robinhood responding in 48 minutes after my interview (by far
                the quickest)!

                Making decisions was extremely difficult as I couldn't just
                intern everywhere like I did last year. I ended up picking
                Robinhood for winter and Two Sigma for summer. For Robinhood, I
                was able to stop by the office during a trip to SF. I enjoyed
                meeting the engineers and getting a peak at the work and
                culture there. I chose Robinhood due to its small company size,
                the team I would be on (order execution), the responsibility I
                would be able to have, and the fact that I am a big fan of the
                product.

                I chose Two Sigma since being at a highly regarded hedge fund
                aligned perfectly with my goal to try finance. Even more, I
                consistently hear great praise about their engineering talent
                and really enjoyed the conversations with my interviewers
                during my onsite. Although I will not know what team I am on
                until later, the team matching process seemed to be very
                flexible in fitting with my interests.

                The recruiting mountain was lifted off my shoulder in early
                November as I signed my offer letters. I enjoyed the rest of
                the semester with some much-needed free time. This experience,
                though stressful and hectic in the moment, was extraordinarily
                educational and beneficial (a post for internship recruiting
                tips is coming). I pushed myself and explored as many
                opportunities as possible. I experienced new companies and new
                industries. I also got much better at organizing and taking
                pictures of receipts.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Internship Search</title>
            <link>https://chy.io/blog/2016/12/2016-recruiting</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 1 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <description>This is a summary of my experience finding a co-op
                during my middler year at Northeastern.

                Here are some stats.

                First interview: 8/16 10:30 am PST
                Last offer signed: 11/23 9:42 am PST
                Companies applied to: 30+
                Companies interviewed with: 15
                Homework challenges: 6
                Total phone interviews: 20
                Onsites: 7
                Total offers: 9
                Offers accepted: 3
                Total hours dedicated: ???
                As a part of Northeastern's co-op program, I have the
                opportunity to take 8 months off school for internships/co-op.
                I was on the hunt for either a long co-op or a few shorter
                internships starting January 2017. (Info about the co-op
                program here)

                The recruiting season kicked off last summer after attending
                the Greylock Techfair. It's a career fair in the Bay Area that
                you have to apply and get invited to. Since the number of
                attendees was limited, it was pretty easy to talk with
                companies. I also went to Internapalooza but there were way too
                many eager interns to be useful (though I did get a lifetime
                supply of T-shirts).

                Although the Techfair put me in touch with a lot of companies,
                my technical abilities were definitely not up to par. I spoke
                with Asana, Airbnb, Coursera, Doordash, Pinterest, and Quora
                but was unable to get past the interview stage. This was a wake
                up call for me to study.

                Being a sheltered CE student a year before, I was blissfully
                unaware of what Cracking the Coding Interview and Leetcode
                were. I was never pressured to practice any graph or dynamic
                programming problems. In order catch up, my classes were placed
                on the back-burners and I began spending a few hours everyday
                on Leetcode.

                By early October, I was feeling a lot more confident in my
                technical abilities and had interviews set up with Google and
                Microsoft. I was also in contact with Facebook through an on
                campus event, Snap through their recruiting event "Snapweek",
                and Dropbox through a referral from a friend's sister. I
                applied to ~15 other companies but had not heard back.
                Northeastern's own co-op recruiting cycle was also beginning to
                ramp up at this time, putting me in touch with companies local
                to Boston.

                After a few weeks, I heard back from both Microsoft and Google
                with good news. Microsoft gave me 2 weeks to decide whereas I
                was placed into the abyss that is Google host matching (up to 6
                weeks of waiting!). At this time, I was midway through Snap's,
                Dropbox's, and Facebook's processes and was scheduling
                onsite/phone interviews. I also had a few onsites with a few
                Boston startups and a hedge fund.


                Visiting the Space Needle in Seattle during Microsoft onsite
                The day before my Microsoft deadline, I was still waiting (and
                about to give up on) Google's host matching. I had final
                interviews lined up for Snap, Facebook, and Dropbox and had a
                few offers from various companies in Boston. Microsoft was
                adamant on not extending their deadline so I regrettably turned
                the offer down.

                The week after, I was rejected by Facebook. And due to
                scheduling issues, my final Snap and Dropbox interviews were
                quite delayed. I continued to double down and turn down
                expiring offers in hopes of working at a Unicorn.

                I wasn't stressed for long, as I soon got a call from Google
                with an interested host and good news from Snap. Both were open
                to 16 week internships, filling up my 8 months off. I turned
                down everywhere else with only a Dropbox onsite a few days
                after.

                I felt very confident going into my Dropbox interview and soon
                had all three offers to choose from. I had a 16 week winter
                offer for Google in Cambridge, a 16 week summer offer for Snap
                in LA, and a 12 week summer offer for Dropbox in SF or NYC. It
                was very difficult to choose between as I have always wanted to
                experience working for Google but am very interested in the
                product at Snap and Dropbox.

                And so... I had the crazy idea of doing all three. In order to
                do so, I needed to shorten Google below their 12 week minimum
                to 11 weeks. I also needed to shorten Snap to 12 weeks and move
                the start date from the summer to the middle of spring. This
                would allow me to work from 1/9 - 9/8 with no breaks in between
                the 3 internships.

                The situation was extremely stressful due to the fact that if
                either Google or Snap were unable to make the changes, I would
                have to go back on what I said and return to the 16 week
                internships. Deadlines were approaching and to make matters
                worse, this was the week before Thanksgiving so responses were
                slow. All I could do was send some emails and wait.

                Then, two days before Thanksgiving and after a week of
                worrying, I was given the okay from both Google and Snap. It
                would be possible for me to work at all three companies in 35
                weeks! I immediately signed all 3 offers and was able to fully
                enjoy my Thanksgiving break.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Hello!</title>
            <link>https://chy.io/blog/2016/11/first-post</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 1 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <description>This will just be a place where I write about tech,
                school, what I'm up to, and various things I find interesting.

                The hope is to post once every month or so.

                If you have any feedback or have topics you want me to cover,
                feel free to contact me!
            </description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>